ZACH BOUDREAUX

SUMMARY

Motivated software engineering graduate from an intensive 800+ hour boot camp at Springboard with 1 year experience in full stack web development and software development. Seeking work to use proven skills in HTML/CSS, JavaScript (NodeJS, ReactJS, Express), and Python (Flask) for a Washington D.C. area company.

PROJECTS

Portfolio Site

Nov. 2021 - Current

Responsive portfolio site I designed to showcase my skills and be a landing page to access other projects I have built.

• Front-End [live link]: React.js, JavaScript, HTML/SCSS

Foodly [live link] Nov. 2021 - Dec. 2021

Second of my two capstone projects. Dynamic, full-stack application utilizing two APIs to search for data on recipes and cocktails and allow you to save these for use later on.

• Front-End [live link]: React.js, JavaScript

• Back-End [live link]: Node.js, Express.js

Movie Database [live link]

July 2021 - July 2021

First of my two capstone projects; an app used to search for movies or tv shows where you can see additional data on them and add them to your personal lists

• Front-End: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

• Back-End: Python, Flask

• Database: PostgreSQL, Flask SQLAlchemy

• Extras: Bcrypt, Flask WTForms

Warbler [live link] Aug. 2021 - Aug. 2021

Built a Twitter clone that allows you to post tweets, like tweets, and follow other users.

• Front-End: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

Back-End: Python, FlaskDatabase: PostgreSQL

TECHNICAL SKILLS

FRONT-END LANGUAGES: JavaScript, HTML/CSS, Bootstrap

BACK-END LANGUAGES: Python, Flask, Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, SQL

CLOUD SYSTEMS: Heroku: Cloud Application Platform, Surge **TECHNICAL QUALIFICATIONS:** Agile Development, Full Stack

SOFTWARE: Git, Homebrew, Microsoft Office Suite, Adobe Software Suite

OPERATING SYSTEMS: Windows, Linux (Ubuntu)

EMPLOYMENT

Springboard, Software Engineering Fellow

Apr. 2021 - Nov. 2021

• 800+ hour comprehensive Software Engineering Bootcamp

• JavaScript, Node.js, Express.js, React.js, Redux JQuery, AJAX, Python, Flask, SQL, HTML, CSS

- Weekly 1-on-1 mentor with an industry professional to help polish my skills
- 4 in-depth portfolio projects

The Compounding Center, Compounding Pharmacy Technician, Leesburg, Virginia

Feb. 2020 -Apr. 2021

While at The Compounding Center, I mixed various chemicals to make formulas specific to the patient when the commercial pharmaceuticals didn't fit their needs.

- Quickly became proficient in RxDispense, a pharmacy management software
- Learned how to work independently while also staying efficient with a strong attention to detail

EDUCATION

Springboard Software Engineering Career Track, Certification

Apr. 2021 - Nov. 2021

Software Engineering Fullstack Web Development 2021